Guide to the Lacey Coe Papers, ca. 1912-1963
Department of Special Collections
Lacey Coe Papers,
ca. 1912-1963
Special Collections M0247
Coe, Lacey.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Lacey Coe, 1974.
Biographical Note
Conductor and composer.
Scope and Content
Summary: Material of Lacey Coe with references to Leopold Auer. Includes photographs, scrapbooks, programs, and clippings.
Container List
- Publications of interest to L. Coe (Folder I:)
  - The Violinist. Sept. 1930, 4 copies
  - Nov. 1931, 1 copy
  - Aug. 1920, 1 copy
  - Manuscript music tablet
  - The Stradivari Memorial
  - Rare Old Violins
- Lacey Coe Violin cellphane envelopes-, 45 items (Folder II:)
- Newspaper Clippings (Folder III:)
  - L. Auer funeral, 8/27/30
  - Baroque Music for Strings with picture of Coe from Miami paper, n.d.
  - Leopold Auer's birthday party, 5/16/25
  - Mother Shipton's Prophecy- a poem, n.d.
  - 5/25/54
  - clippings about Coe and recitals, 1963
  - Recital announcements, clippings from Palm Beach papers, 1946
  - Eugene Yeaye, 1931
- Magazine article
  - My Adventures with Young Geniuses, Leopold Auer Leopold Auer interview- Musical Observer 1920
- Princeton newspapers
  including the Packet Princeton Herald, Daily Princetonian 1926-1931. six issues.
- A Visit with Jascha Heifetz by Don Murray, Sat. Evening Post
- Programs and Announcements (Folder IV:)
  - Chicago Ensemble Trio, n.d.
  - Program, 1912
  - Program, 1914
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 1918
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 1920; (2 copies)
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 1925
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 1926; (6 copies)
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 6/3/27:
  - Yearbook of the Great National American Music Festival, 9/12/27:; (2 copies)
  - Announcement of Lacey Coe Violin School, 9/12/27:; (3 copies)
  - Announcement of Lacey Coe Violin School, 1928:
  - Programs, 1928:
  - 1929:
  - 4/3/31:
  - (3), 5/9/31:
  - 12/16/34:
  - (3), 2/16/36:
  - 6/14/36:
  - 5/12/37:
  - (3), 12/27/38:
  - 12/8/38:
  - 12/11/38:
  - (2), 6/24/38:
  - Programs (2), 7/23/39:
  - (7), 5/15/38:
  - (3), 5/12/37:
  - (3), 5/9/38:
  - (8), 6/11/39:
  - (7), 6/ 9/40:
  - (35), 6/ 1/41:
  - 3/29/31:
  - (5), 5/5/42:
  - (2), 2/24/44:
  - (3), 6/11/44:
  - 3/16/45:
  - 1/11/46:
  - 1/11/47:
  - 5/ 3/53:
  - Program of L. Coe Violin School Student recital, n.d.
- Letters and notes (Folder V:)
  - Leopold Auer as an American, by an American including the original pencil draft by Coe, 1 carbon copy, 1 typescript
  - Original letter from Auer endorsign Coe for his school, 17 Jan. 1927
  - to L. Coe from A. E. Taylor. editor of The Violinist, 17 July 1930
  - to L. Coe from G. M. Purver, copy of poem tribute to L. Auer later published in The Violinist, 14 Dec 1926
  - To L. Coe from Ida Day, 7 May 1942
  - telegram to Mr. and Mrs. L. Coe from Wanda and L. Auer, Christmas greetings
  - to Mr. Coe from H. W. Dodds (president of Princeton Univ) 14 June '34
  - to Whom it may concern from Harry M. Halbrook of The Billboard, recommendation of L. Coe, 21 Oct 1918
  - To L. Coe from Capt. Arthur A. Clappé (director Army Music School), 11 Dec 1918
  - Program notes- rough draft
  - pencil notes on Mazie O'Dell Cardy, Phillip Frank, Coe's son
  - note to Mr. John Dubbs
- Photographs and Programs belonging to Lydia Pearl Coe (Lacey Coe's sister) (Folder VI:)
  - Photos- Wanda Auer, Coe and dog, Mrs. Mazie O'Dell Cardy (?), various students of Coe, group photo including L. Coe, portraits of Coe with violin, Coe's niece
  - Programs- Lacey Coe Recital (3) 24 June 1938,Lydia Coe Recital, various church programs in which Lydia Coe sang
- Public relations pamphlet
- Newspaper clippings-
  - Chicago Daily Tribune 12 June 1915
  - laminated announcement of recital
  - Miami Herald 3 June 1945
- Bulletin Friends of Music 15 Dec 1938
- Biblical references in address of 7 Oct 1916
- Photographs (Folder VII:)
  - Orchestra with Lacey Coe as concert master (2)
  - Soldier
  - Auer with 5 pupils, Zimbalist? Heifetz?
  - Air Corps pilot
  - Elderly Mr. and Mrs. Coe
  - Coe on back of car
  - Young Coe and Wilson Peak
  - Violinist, William Karsh
  - 2 shots of a baby
  - snapshot of man on horse
  - snapshot of man with horse
  - Elderly Lacey and Lydia Coe, 3 color snapshots
  - Young violinist, Sam Rosenblum, 30 May 1925
  - William Kurash
  - Group shot including elderly Coes
  - Group shot including elderly Coes
  - Group shot including elderly Coes
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe and family
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe and family
  - Woman
  - Color shot of elderly Mr. Coe at recital
  - Color shot of elderly Mr. Coe at recital
  - Lacey Coe, middle age
  - Older Lacey Coe
  - Elderly Lacey Coe with wife
  - Group shot including Lacey Coe
  - Eight pupils
  - Young Coe with violin-publicity portrait (24)
  - Snapshot of Coe at N.Y. Riverdale
  - Mrs. Auer or Mrs. Coe and four pupils
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe
  - Coe at dinner
  - Coe at dinner
  - Arthur Abell and Leopold Auer
  - Two children
  - Mrs. Coe receiving corsage at reception
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe with Lydia Coe (?) and Mrs. Auer at reception
  - Duplicate of above
  - Four elderly women
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe shaking hands with guests
  - Paul Nochanski 1930autographed
  - Auer photo - autographed
  - Elderly Coe at reception
  - Mr. and Mrs. Coe at reception
  - Old picture of man, woman and two children
  - Young woman, Mrs. Coe (?) and Lydia Coe (?), 2 prints
  - Same woman in white dress, 3 prints
  - Coe and Auer and G.M. Parver (3) Citizenship picture
  - L. Auer 1923autographed
  - L. Auer
  - Side view of a woman
  - Joseph, a pupil
  - Shumsky and Zimbalist
  - Four pupils (incl. Joseph) playing
  - Joseph
  - Negative of photo of Lydia Coe
  - Boy with violin (Folder VIII:)
  - Three children, one of whom is boy with violin
  - Mish Auer with woman
  - Six pictures of Mish Auer in various poses
  - Two pictures of man
  - Three shots of Romeo and Juliet production (?)
  - Framed picture of L. Coe and Mrs. Auer
  - Samuel L. Crocker
  - Snapshot of Lacey Coe and child
  - Fred Plotkin, a pupil
  - Raymond, a pupil
  - Tom Mesdog
  - American Operatic Quarter including Pearl Coe
- 40 pages including programs, e.g. Concert of 80th Birthday of Leopold Auer; newspaper clippings, memorabilia, correspondence to Professor Auer. (Othertype 1: (A))
- 50 pages of: (Othertype 2:)
  - newspaper clippings- Philip Frank at Grammans Chinese Theater, 1910, 1913, 1916
  - programs- 80th birthday of Leopold Auer, Lacey Coe Violin school
  - letters- to Sister Rundle from Gahfia Blanchard to Lacey Coe from Leopold Auer post card from Auer
  - notes on Chicago Hebrew Institute recital 1923
  - contract- Sept. 29, 1922; Oct. 9, 1922.
  - Leopold Auer as an American, by an American
  - Certificate of lifetime membership, Miami Music Teachers Association. 1954
  - Photo portrait of a bride in flowing gown Photo of Lacey Coe, Leopold Auer & G. M. Purver (2) (Othertype 2:(B))
  - Framed portrait of Lacey Coe, Leopold Auer and G. M. Purver. Addressed to Coe, signed by Auer on the occasion of his naturalisation (Othertype 2:(C))
  - Framed photo of Auer, signed by Auer (Othertype 2:(D))
  - Photo of Mr. and Mrs. Leopold Auer (Othertype 2:(F))
  - L. Coe and Wanda Auer framed picture in box with pictures of L. Coe and duplicate of framed picture
  - Long photo of orchestra with elderly L. Coe as concert master
  - Three reels of recording mix
  - Box of plastic animals on cards, notes in cyrillic alphabet on back